You wanted to show us what a
boss fight looks like, first?
That's part of it. But not all.
My leg!
Even if you lose, you won't die.
Like I said.
There's no shame for an adventurer
in avoiding a fight you can't win.
Maybe you're right.
But no, that's not what I meant!
If I run away here, I don't
think I'll ever come back.
I'll never be a real adventurer.
Ryze...
You've made your decision, then.
Magical
Contract
A Grand Slime...
We won't mess up like those guys did.
Let's be the ones to tell
the guild we beat it!
This didn't go like I was hoping.
There's no actual need to
beat the boss for this exam.
Honestly, I was hoping those other
examinees would beat it for us.
But, well, it's important to
encounter some challenges in life.
I can see through your attacks!
Aim for its core!
Focus on empowering your magic.
These two are capable of
defeating a Grand Slime.
Listen to me. Physical attacks
will barely work at all.
Magic's what you'll need to win.
Can you use powerful fire magic?
Yes, a little...
But it'll take time to activate.
Don't worry.
I'll block its attacks while you're casting.
Wait. Can you let me be the one to do that?
Rentt, help Ryze! I'm fine on my own!
Here I go!
Grand Pyrox!
We got it!
Finish it before it regenerates!
Right!
We did it!
Yeah. We beat the boss!
Rentt?
Slime fluids are worth a lot.
Let's gather them up.
Even if we split the money among the three
of us, we'll get at least one silver each.
See you there!
Well, I don't think it matters.
I knew you'd figure it out.
Just like I thought.
A sleeping gas trap?
Right before the goal is one of the
places people let their guard down most.
Not that it really matters if
they get there ahead of us.
What do you mean?
Getting there first doesn't
mean passing, does it?
Think back really carefully.
The guild didn't say a word about that.
Your job is to reach the
point written on your map.
The first party to arrive will receive
a reward befitting their efforts.
They set it up so we'd think
it was a race, but...
That's why Rentt didn't mind
letting the other party go ahead,
even when we were in front of the boss room.
That's a mean trap.
I feel stupid for worrying.
An adventurer's only job is to complete
the task before the deadline.
It wouldn't have killed
them to tell us that.
You can't be a real adventurer
unless you can think for yourself.
Congratulations.
You're the first here.
Are you real?
Show us proof you're with the guild.
Is this enough for you?
Yes. Thank you.
Take these, then.
Show these to the guild's front desk and
you'll become Bronze-class adventurers.
Hey, what's that bonus that
you guys talked about?
Oh, the first three teams
get a little bonus.
Here. Potions and a case for them.
I've been wanting one of these!
So that's what that was about.
Hey, you two.
Can we make a side trip before we go home?
This is the 2nd floor, right?
Do you know what it's like?
No.
The labyrinths are beyond
human understanding.
You'll realize that up ahead.
Why is there a sun underground?
I'd heard that each floor was
totally different, but...
Wow.
This is the world you're about to enter.
We're...
Hey, hey.
Let's take a little look around.
That's a bad idea.
The exam's not over until we're back.
It feels like it's been so long
since I've seen this building.
There were traps on the way home
too, just like we thought.
Remember what I said? The guild...
...can be mean!
Okay, good work!
With this, the Bronze-class examination
comes to an end for real.
Does this mean we're Bronze-class now?
Well...
Sister, they'll be fine.
Here's the report.
I see.
In that case...
What's going on?
He was watching us the whole
time during the exam.
I had no idea!
The exam also tests what
kind of person you are.
We can't raise your rank if we decide you're
not the right kind of person for it.
And so we...
You pass without problems.
Now you're real Bronze-class adventurers!
We passed...
Did you hear that, Laura?
She says we passed!
We did it, Ryze!
I'm so glad we left the village!
Yeah! It was worth coming even when
Mom and Dad didn't want me to!
What they're saying kind of scares me...
Thanks for coming with me!
Well, it happens a lot.
We need to go tell them.
So I'm Bronze-class again now...
Ryze, Laura. Thanks for
coming with me today.
No, that's our line.
We won't forget what you taught us today.
Rentt, thanks to you, I think we've
finally become real adventurers.
Ryze...
I'd like to ask you to keep
adventuring with us...
but that's impossible, isn't it?
It feels like your goal is
somehow different than ours.
That's why you told us all that
stuff during the exam, right?
So we could make it on our own.
Yeah.
You may have only been a part
of our party for one day,
but you're still a treasured comrade.
Yeah. Let's adventure again sometime!
They're good kids, huh?
Yeah. I felt like a parent
more than anything.
But they might've been working hard
to make me feel welcome, too.
Rentt.
I have a question for you.
I apologize for asking when you're
tired, but will you come with me?
You're sharp enough to know
what I want to ask, aren't you?
Sheila knows who I really am.
Does the Guild intend to punish
me for what I've done?
I'm asking the questions here.
If that's the case, I'll never
come back to this guild.
That's all.
Wait!
I just want to know...
What exactly happened to you?
I thought about running away.
But I couldn't.
Her voice was the voice of a woman who was
genuinely worried about an old friend.
Sheila, I've got a big problem
I'm dealing with right now.
I don't want anyone getting
involved. Not even the guild.
Rentt, I actually haven't told
the guild about you, yet.
Sheila... Why?
Part of it was that I wasn't sure.
But more than anything, I wanted
to see the truth for myself.
I've told the man who was watching
you during the exam a little, but...
He's my brother.
He can keep a secret.
Would you please tell me
what's happening to you?
It's hard to trust me, isn't it?
So I've prepared this.
A magical contract?
Yes.
If the contract detailed here is broken,
in this case, if I share your secret,
I'll suffer a penalty
backed by magical force.
If she does not carry out
her end of the contract,
Sheila Ibarss will leave the guild, travel
to a country where slavery is legal,
and perform the necessary paperwork to
transfer ownership of herself to another party.
No, no, no. That's way too heavy!
Why go that far?
I want to help you, and not
because I'm part of the guild.
Why?
Because it's thanks to you that I grew up.
Sheila...
You don't realize it, but there are a
lot of people who are grateful to you.
All right. I'll sign.
And then I'll tell you.
Right.
Now, where to begin...
It would be faster to show you, I think.
Terrifying, isn't it?
I bet you regret asking.
No! That's not true...
It's not...
If you're suffering that much...
I'd much rather know.
But how did this happen?
I've turned into a monster.
I'm an undead right now.
Is that possible?
I can see why you'd feel
distressed hearing this.
So I want you to think about
it again before you answer...
Can you really help me?
Of course, I have no intention
of harming anyone.
But that's a different question from
whether you can believe me or not.
Wait!
I believe you!
I believe you're a monster now,
and that you won't attack anyone!
Because... Because... you
were always such a good guy!
Those kids... and me, too...
We all owe you so much.
So I'll help you.
Rentt, if something happens between
you and the guild, tell me.
I promise... I promise I'll help you.
Oh!
I'm sorry for coming at this hour.
I insisted on coming to speak with you.
Well, you're certainly a rare guest.
Rentt, don't tell me you've
been messing around with her.
He hasn't.
But I've learned a lot about him.
I see.
Well, that's fine.
Come inside.
It's not very clean, though, I'm afraid.
I cleaned it up before I left...
All right. I suppose I should
just come out and ask.
How much did you hear?
Rentt told me he's a monster.
And that he's not going to attack anyone.
Oh, that's everything!
And yet you came all the way out here?
That's awfully naïve of you.
What do you mean by that?
Think about it.
Rentt is an undead.
And I'm a sketchy-looking academic.
What do you think happens to a young
girl who wanders into the home
of a witch and a monster?
Normally, you could expect to be thrown
into a boiling pot and end up in my stomach.
Aw, you're no witch.
Everyone knows you're a
wonderful researcher.
Oh no, that's just what
I've made everyone think!
Actually, my hobby is going out at night
to hunt the blood of young maidens!
It makes my skin so beautiful.
That's what Rentt's become.
Lorraine doesn't see Sheila as a person,
even as she's sitting in front of her.
Depending on her answer, she'll
eliminate her without hesitation.
I... know that.
I know that.
I see. Good, then.
I'm not saying it to be mean.
And it's late.
Let's have dinner together.
O-Okay!
Thank you for the meal.
I heard you were a good cook, Rentt. I
guess everyone who said that was right.
I learned in my home village.
It's handy, having him around.
He'll do all the chores for you.
And the price, if I were to
call it that... is that, for now.
I see.
Ghasts are a type of
low-ranking vampire, aren't they?
That's right.
Now, you two made a magical contract?
Yes. She won't share who I am.
Yes. But you've been standing out lately...
I have?
There are lots of rookie adventurers going
missing right now, all over the kingdom.
They haven't just been killed by monsters?
If that happened, their
stuff should be left behind.
The guild is assuming it's
a series of kidnappings.
I see. And they have a suspect
who looks extremely suspicious,
and is also highly skilled.
Specifically, Rentt, correct?
He's certainly not acting like a rookie...
Some are spreading rumors
about him out of jealousy.
Wow, people are jealous of me now?
Hey! It's not a good thing!
That's right.
You're in a delicate position right now.
If it's that bad, I can stop going
into the labyrinth for a while.
How many days is "a while," exactly?
Three days or so.
What?
Okay... four.
I hope we get someone good.
Yeah.
Once we've got a party, we're going
down to the second floor again.
Yeah.
We didn't get to go anywhere last time,
so let's fight a whole lot of monsters!
Work hard, rookies.
Hey, I heard Rentt Vivie
passed his exam, too.
His skills and personality were just fine.
I see.
Yes.
Speaking of Rentts...
What happened to Rentt Faina?
I was planning on recruiting him
to the guild once he retired.
"Forgot"?
What am I supposed to do?
Look. One of the new kids is in trouble.
I-I'll go right away!
But Guildmaster, the other Rentt
is a wonderful adventurer, too!
A New Weapon and Power